The Princess Sapphire
Knight of the Ribbon
Atashi no miru yume himitsu nano
The dreams I see are my secret
Dare ni mo iwanai himitsu nano
I won’t tell anyone—it’s my secret
Akai manto hira hira
A red cape fluttering
Uma o tobasu oujo
Galloping on a horse—the princess
Sore ga atashi
That’s me!
Lula dula lula dula
Lulu laa, lulaa
Ribon no kishi wa
The Knight of the Ribbon,
Honto wa hontto wa
Truly, truly,
Atashi nano sa
It’s really me!
Forty-Fourth Episode
The Snow Eagle
It’s your turn, doctor.
Your knight is in danger,
so watch out for the next move!
It's up to you to play, doctor.
Today you're a bit distracted!
Oh, excuse me!
Let me see!
So... Yes, it seems to me
that you've made a good move!
- There! What do you think?
- Not bad! Not bad!
And after this other move, what will you do?
There's something wrong
with the doctor!
He always likes
playing chess so much...
But today he is so distracted!
- Doctor!
- It's my turn, good! So... There!
Doctor, perhaps it’s
better to stop playing!
If there is something
worrying you, please tell me!
Forgive me, it’s really a silly thing,
but I can't stop thinking about it!
It’s snowing a lot! They say it hasn't
snowed this much in a hundred years!
It has already been
snowing for five days straight!
And what is wrong with that?
There is a legend about an eagle, Princess!
- An eagle?
- It is said that the snow eagle
...it brings a bad omen,
if it appears after a snowfall!
The snow eagle
that brings a bad omen?
Exactly!
It arrives after a heavy snowfall!
And when it covers the country
with its great wings,
it is a harbinger
of some great misfortune!
And you were worried about this?
After all, it is nothing more
than a legend!
Yes! But old legends always
have a foundation of truth!
And this scares me a little!
In the past, every time
a misfortune occurred,
there has always been
a premonitory sign!
What was that noise, doctor?
Princess, the snow eagle...
...that brings the bad omen
has already appeared as I feared!
See? What did I tell you?
Here is the symbol of the bad omen!
Frankly, I was struck
much more...
...by the sound we heard
last night.
Sapphire! Sapphire!
Sapphire, why don't you come down?
So we can make a snowman!
All right, Tink, I'm coming down!
I'll be down in a minute!
I have already finished, Sapphire!
Tell me, what do you think
of my snowman?
Not bad!
But who is it supposed to be?
It's strange that you don't
recognize the Masked Knight!
- Don't be like that!
- The Masked Knight isn't like that!
He's taller, more elegant, thinner!
And besides, he's more handsome!
Yours! It's Franz!
- Here he comes!
- What?! Franz?!
Hello, guys!
I'm happy to see you.
I didn't come sooner because
of the snowfall. Hi, Tink!
I am glad you came!
What are you doing?
Can you show it to me?
So I can play with you too!
We were making snowmen.
Look, that one is mine!
- But it's me!
- Do you recognize yourself in that snowman?
Certainly!
You made it look just like me!
Now I will make
a snowman that looks like you
I think I'd better
leave them alone!
How beautiful! It's like being
in Heaven again!
It's like a garden
of white flowers!
Oh..! I heard a noise!
Try to recover, old man!
Come on!
Come on, tell me what happened, please!
- He has regained consciousness!
- You are a citizen of Silverland!
Take me to the castle,
I must warn the King!
Union X is coming
with a terrible weapon!
Your snowman
is much more beautiful than mine!
No, yours is much better!
Look!
Sapphire, in reality I didn't
only come here to play with you.
I would like to discover the origin
of this mysterious sound!
Sapphire! Sapphire!
Sapphire... Sapphire...
Union X has reached
...bringing with it
a terrible weapon!
Indeed, it is a horrible weapon!
The border guards
have all been killed!
- What?!
Sapphire, that sound could
come from Union X's weapon!
I'm going to explore the forest
of orange trees, will you come with me?
Tink, show me the way!
Wait for me!
How will you get there without me?
Tink, are you sure
it’s right here?
Of course! I’m sure
this is the place.
But it’s completely
deserted! Not a soul in sight!
Franz, I have the feeling
that someone is watching us!
You know, to tell you the
truth, I have the same feeling too!
Watch out!
Who are you? Come out of there!
We are the patrol squad
of Union X!
You won’t leave here alive!
- Sapphire!
- Yes, Franz!
Take this!
Good job, Tink!
We’ll tear you to pieces!
Come on!
Look, we've put them to flight!
Don't claim victory yet! You're in for something very interesting!
Too bad for you! You can't imagine the end that awaits you!
I don't know what we should expect, but I'm not afraid!
This noise...
- Sapphire!
- Here I am, Franz, I'm here!
Hey, is everything okay?
- Yes! Everything's fine!
- Get down!
The eagle of ill omen?!
I want to see for myself!
Wait, Franz, we're coming with you!
Load!
Fire!
Our cannon will reduce Silverland Castle
...to a pile of ruins!
Let's move forward!
Keep going like this!
Set course for Silverland!
So that noise was the roar of the cannon!
A disaster will happen if that big cannon crosses the border!
We must prevent it at all costs!
Right! We will prevent it! That weapon will not enter Silverland!
- Sapphire, do you have any good ideas?
- Yes! Look down there!
We will collapse the bridge over the river that marks the border!
Luckily, they didn't
destroy the guard post.
There must be some
gunpowder there!
That seems like a good
idea! We'll blow up the bridge.
What will we do if those
soldiers try to occupy the Fortress?
We'll do everything to defeat them!
Oh no, it's about to leave!
Tink, we've beaten
them all, you can come!
Look! Here are the
barrels of gunpowder.
It should be enough. The
problem is how to transport it.
I've got an idea!
We'll build a sled...
...and we will bring
you the gunpowder!
Let's go!
Come on, gallop, little horses!
Good! Like that! Hurray! Cheers!
Hold on, Tink, or you'll
be thrown to the ground!
Let's catch up to them!
- The Union squad!
- What?!
- Are they already chasing us?
- Come on! Faster!
Watch out, Sapphire!
The soldiers have skis...
...with sharp points!
- Really?!
Good heavens!
Dammit! The sled!
- What's happening, Sapphire?
- They've detached the horses.
- We'll have to steer the sled ourselves!
- What?!
Sapphire and Tink are in danger!
- Sapphire!
- Franz!
We're going to crash into the bridge!
Help!
- Tink, is everything okay?
- Yes, everything's okay!
Watch out, Tink!
Sapphire, I'm afraid these soldiers
are too many for you, you know?
I'm coming, Sapphire!
Franz, all the gunpowder
has fallen into the river!
There's nothing more to be done!
So for now let's go back to the Fortress.
- Dammit! - They hit her!
- Yes, they hit her!
- By now it's been razed to the ground!
- We must hide!
Fire!
There's a gorge further ahead,
we can hide there!
How come my glove
got scorched?
I've got it! That icicle acted
as a lens and burned the glove!
Yeah, a lens!
It's an idea! If we used
the icicles as lenses...
This gorge is not big and one can
easily trigger an avalanche!
That way, perhaps, we can block
that big cannon!
Luckily the sun is still high!
Maybe we'll succeed!
Guys, we have to look
for a piece of ice!
- As big as possible!
- All right!
We must hurry
or we won't make it!
I thought I'd easily find
pieces of ice in so much snow,
but now I don't see
even one!
Who knows what Sapphire wants
to do with the ice!
I'm on the ice.
Help! I'm slipping!
Sapphire!
There it is!
Haven't you finished yet?
The ice is heavy!
Hang in there, Tink,
try to hold on a little longer!
We're almost finished. There!
There is a danger of avalanches
here; if we make noise, they will bury us!
Put out that fire!
I finally understand!
- You want to blow up the cannon...
...with the ice lens!
- Yes, of course!
Since we have the
sun on our side...
We must try!
Shine on our glories, sun!
Celebrate the invasion of Silverland!
Look at how powerful
we are with our weapons!
Union X will conquer the world!
And you will see our banners
on every continent!
Good heavens! I missed my aim!
Franz, we must immediately
direct the beam onto the fuse!
We are being attacked from above!
Archers, quick!
Be careful, Franz!
Don't expose yourself too much! Take cover!
Yes! But you be careful
of the arrows too!
Damn,
they grazed me!
Shoot! Kill them!
The fuse will catch fire!
The avalanche!
- Help!
- Let's run!
Sapphire! Tink!
Hold on tight to the tree!
- Franz, how are you?
- Fine. And you, are you safe and sound?
Of course! Everything is fine!
Let's see what became
of the cannon!
Hurray, we have destroyed
Union X!
The cannon by now
is buried forever under the snow!
Look, the sun is melting
the snow eagle!
But the Union can rise again,
so we must be ready...
...to defend ourselves
at any moment.
You know, Franz, we must maintain
peace at all costs.
And so we will have to be
always united to defend it.
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Sen'nen man'nen hyakuman-nen
A thousand years, ten thousand years, a million years,
Ribbon de tsunagou ichioku-nen
Let’s connect with ribbons for a billion years!
Akuma ga kute mo arashi ga kute mo
Even if devils come, even if storms arrive,
tsunaida kokoro wa hanarenai
Our bonded hearts will never part.
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Subtitled by
SilverlandSubs
tinyurl.com/SilverlandSubs
Opening & Ending Song Lyrics Translation by
Natalia Arlovskaya
lyricstranslate.com/en/
translator/natalia-arlovskaya
EAN-13 : 8-031179-423880
ASIN : ‎ B0DQ54LVY1
EAN-13 : 8-031179-426225
ASIN : ‎ B0F1V5YTQP